Finding Aid for the Gilbert A. Harrison collection of material by and relating to Gertrude Stein LSC.2108
UCLA Library Special Collections
- "Brewsle and Willie," n.p., ca. 1945-46[?].; 61pp. Typescript (carbon) and typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  With this is a letter of transmittal from Gertrude Stein to Bill Walton. n.p., n.d. 1 leaf (2pp.) Autograph letter (signed), with transcript.
  Purchase, Minkoff, 1985.
- Fisher, M.F.K. "Toasting Toklas," Vanity Fair, (November 1984).; pp.86-88, 90, 115-116. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  From a foreword to a new edition of Alice B. Toklas's Cook Book.
  Gift of David S. Zeidberg, 1984.
- [Christmas card with illustration of Gertrude Stein]. [Chicago, [1982].; 1 item. 12.5 cm. × 17.5 cm Printed. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  On the cover; "Paris, 1906; Gertrude Stein listens as a young artist named Claus discusses his plans to abandon cubism in favor of a wild new project. Miss Stein is dubious."
  Immediate Source of Acquisition note
  Gift of Lilace Hatayama, 1985.
- Letter to [Bill] Walton. [Paris, ]., ca. 1945-1946; 2 leaves (4pp.) Holograph. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  Bill Walton was the nephew of Stein's friend, Emily Chadbourne.
  Stein thanks Walton for the package of food sent to them during the war shortages. She mentions that Brewsie and Willie is coming out in May, and that she has written an opera about Susan B. Anthony.
  Purchase, Minkoff, 1986.
- Letter to Mr. Lescher. Paris, 25 January 1963.; 1 leaf (2pp.) Typescript with holograph corrections. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  re Alice B. Tolklas.
- Oversize scrapbooks. (Box 8)
- Photograph of plaque at Bilignin, summer home of Gertrude Stein and Alice B. Toklas. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  Negative available.
- "Identity" by Gertrude Stein., Typescript carbon copies. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  With copies of related correspondence.
  Gift of Burdette Fitzgerald.
- Copies of winning essays for "Considering Gertrude Stein," UCLA Extension, Fall 1984. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  Gift of Jim Hartzell.